She's back! She's home!
她回來了 她終於回到家了
Philippa came home!
菲利帕回家了
Two years,
兩年過去了
and everything looks exactly as I remember.
一切都和記憶中一模一樣
I never thought I would see this place again.
我以為再也見不到這裡了
There were 18 of us this time.
這一次我們有18個人
Culled from every corner of the Empire
從帝國各個角落被選中
and brought to Terra for the contest.
帶到地球參加比試
We were told that only one of us would survive
他們說只有一個人能活到最後
the years to come.
熬過這些年
One child.
一個孩子…
...the purest expression of the Terran identity.
…最純粹的帝國血脈
They pitted us against each other.
他們讓我們自相殘殺
And month by month, our numbers dwindled.
一個月又一個月 我們的人數不斷減少
Did...did you win?
你...你贏了嗎
ls it over?
結束了嗎
Two of us still live.
還剩下兩個人
San and me.
桑和我
Me and San.
我和桑
We are two...
我們是二人
...but one.
…卻如一人
Forever.
永遠如此
The word "friend" was forbidden during the contest,
比試期間“朋友”這個詞是被禁止的
but we whispered it to each other when no one could hear.
但無人時我們會悄悄對彼此說出這個詞
San and I combined our skills
桑和我聯手對抗
against the proctor and the other contestants.
總督和其他參賽者
But only one of you could be emperor.
但只能有一個人成為皇帝
One task remains.
還剩最後一個任務
The first to complete it rules the Empire,
誰先完成誰就能統治帝國
and the other spends the rest of their life
另一個人餘生都將
in servitude to the new emperor.
侍奉新皇帝
What do you have to do?
你們要做什麼
I'm sorry.
對不起
What did you do? !
你做了什麼
No ties to the old life are permitted.
不允許與過去有任何牽絆
An emperor can only be loyal to duty.
皇帝只能忠於職責
"Thus does the Empire remain strong.
帝國因此而強大
Thus does it grow. "
帝國因此而強盛”
Mom. Philippa.
-媽媽 -菲利帕
You succeeded where your competitor could not.
你成功了 而你的對手失敗了
Bring him here.
把他帶上來
San did not have the strength to pass the final test.
桑沒有力量通過最後的考驗
Even now, his village burns as a testament to his cowardice.
此刻他的村莊正在燃燒 昭示著他的懦弱
I love you.
我愛你
You have won the contest.
你贏了這場較量
Claim your victory.
來領取你的勝利吧
San, step forward.
桑 上前來
You live now only to serve at her heel.
你如今只為臣服於她而活
Kneel before the one who owns your life.
跪拜吧 向掌控你生命的人
We are two...
我們本為二者…
But one.
卻合為一體
Not anymore.
但這一切已經結束了
AII hail Philippa Georgiou!
向喬治歐陛下致敬
AlI hail the emperor!
向帝王致敬
Hail! Hail! Hail!
致敬 致敬 致敬
Hail!
致敬
This is Control
這裡是指揮部
with a priority message for Alpha Team Leader.
向阿爾法小隊隊長發送優先度消息
Your subject is Emperor Philippa Georgiou,
你的目標是菲利帕 喬治歐
former ruler of the Terran Empire.
特倫帝國的前任統治者
lt's in a parallel universe
她來自一個平行宇宙
with the most criminal population
那裡的罪犯數量之多
in recorded history.
史無前例
Even there, Georgiou had the market cornered on atrocities.
即便在那裡 喬治歐的暴行也是最令人髮指的
ln 2257, she was brought to our universe
2257年 她被帶到我們的宇宙
and joined Section 31,
加入了31區
but after a few years, we lost contact.
但幾年後我們失去了聯繫
Recently, Georgiou was spotted using an alias
最近 喬治歐用假身份出現
in the border territory outside Federation space,
在聯邦空間外的邊境地帶
where we're tracking a new threat on the black market.
我們正在那裡追蹤黑市上的一個新威脅
This is where your team comes in.
這就是你們小隊的任務
Federation treaty forbids us from crossing over that border,
聯邦條約禁止我們越過那條邊境線
which means Starfleet cannot get its hands dirty.
這意味著星際艦隊不能直接插手
You and your 31 team will go in, make contact with Georgiou
你和你的31區小隊將潛入 與喬治歐取得聯繫
to help identify and neutralize the threat.
幫助識別並消除這個威脅
But make no mistqke...
但要記住…
this dog bites, so watch your backs.
這條惡犬會咬人 小心你們的後背
You have 24 hours to complete the mission.
你們有24小時完成任務
Get to work.
開始行動吧
Madame du Franc?
杜弗朗克夫人
Small incident in the honeymoon suite.
蜜月套房發生了點小意外
I'm afraid the bride molted
恐怕那位新娘在關鍵時刻
just as things were coming to a climax.
蛻皮了
Virgil, get to the point. -
維吉爾 說重點
I sent a biohazard team and your condolences.
我已派惡靈古堡小組前去 並轉達了您的慰問
Also, there's a customer hoping for a word with you.
另外 有位客人希望能與您談談
He seems entirely sober but quite intoxicating.
他看起來很清醒 但卻令人著迷
Mqdame Veronique du Franc will see you.
杜弗朗克夫人願意見您
Alok Sahar, Madame Veronique du Franc.
阿洛克 薩哈爾 見過杜弗朗克夫人
Madame du Franc normally does business by appointment.
杜弗朗克夫人通常需要預約才見客
I'd like to make an oppointment.
我想預約
Oh, the gentleman would like to make an appointment.
哦 這位先生想預約呢
Now. Now, madam.
現在 現在 夫人
Impossible.Impossible.
不可能 不可能
Au revoir, Virgil.
再見 維吉爾
That is illegal.
這是違法的
And that makes money.
而這能賺錢
This is a reputable establishment.
這是家正經場所
Not what I heard.
我聽說不是
- Why don't we discuss it in your office? - umm.
不如去你辦公室談談 嗯？
Why would I take you to my office, Alok Sahar?
我為什麼要帶你去我的辦公室 阿洛克 薩哈爾？
Because it's a hands- on experience.
因為這需要親身體驗
Dulcet thistle.
甜薊花
Dulcet thistle's extinct.
甜薊花已經滅絕了
I've got a dozen keys of this stuff.
我有十二公斤這東西
Have you partaken?
要來點嗎？
This would be one of my few first times.
這會是我少有的第一次體驗之一
Packs a punch.
勁很大
- Ahappy punch. Mmm.
讓人愉悅的那種
Bottoms up.
乾杯
- To money. To you.
為金錢 為你
Now, let's cut the shit.
現在 別裝了
What is Section 31 doing in my space station?
31區來我的太空站做什麼?
umm? You think I don't know an agent when I see one?
嗯？以為我認不出特工嗎？
You're heading up a team of six operatives,
你帶著六名特工
and they're dll over the bar.
他們都在酒吧裡
There's the Chameloid,
那邊那個變形者
a green- blooded shape- shifter,
綠血的變種人
trying to muster sexy time with a Deltan,
正試圖勾引一個德爾塔人
a walking honey trap
一個活生生的誘餌
31's obviously using as a distraction.
31區顯然在用她轉移注意力
Except Chameloids are the only species in the galaxy
但變形者是銀河系唯一
immune to Deltan sexy time charm.
對德爾塔人魅力免疫的種族
Then there's the guy with all the high- end mech,
還有那邊那個全身高科技裝備的傢伙
standing in the back, looking like he has thoughts.
站在後面一副若有所思的樣子
Mech life, it ain't just about the brute force.
機械生命不只是靠蠻力
I'mgonna say heavy on artillery, low on IQ.
我猜 武器很重 智商很輕
I'm so sorry.
真遺憾
And we can't forget the Vulcan,
別忘了那個瓦肯人
laughing way too hard at the stage banter.
笑得比台上的笑話還誇張
And since Vulcans never laugh, he's either an idiot, too,
瓦肯人從不笑所以他要麼也是個蠢貨
or lost his mind during pon farr and went insane.
要麼是龐法導致精神失常
Oh, come on. That was funny.
得了吧 這很好笑
And the very serious human you stuck him with.
還有你安排的那個一本正經的人類…
Reel it in anytime.
收斂點吧
...she's got a stick so far up her backside,
她屁股裡的棍子插得太深了
it's coming out her mouth.
都從嘴裡冒出來了
Just reel it in.
收斂點
That would be
那是
Lieutenant Garrett.
加勒特中尉
Starfleet.
星際艦隊
Where fun goes to die.
歡樂的終結者
It took you long enough to find me.
你們找到我花了夠久的
We knew that having you here on the Baraam
我們知道你在巴拉姆
would be valuable to us one day.
總有一天會對我們有用
Well, I'm not feeling motivated to be valuable
我現在可沒什麼動力
to anyone but myself.
為別人效力
So, is this where we start negotiating?
那麼 我們是不是該開始談條件了？
umm, that depends.
嗯 那要看情況
How long have you known about me?
你知道我多久了
Ever since you took over from the previous owner,
從你接手前任店主開始
who we still haven't found.
那人至今下落不明
Well, all of.
聽著
That wasn't me. Emperor Georgiou,
-不是我做的 -皇帝
I am authorized to arrest you
我被授權逮捕你
and wipe your mind clean. -
並抹除你的記憶
But then again, there's a part of me
但我內心有個聲音
that wants you to live with your memories.
想讓你繼續帶著這些記憶活著
The genocidal ones.
那些大屠殺的記憶
Being authorized to arrest me
你有權逮捕我
isn't the same as being able to arrest me.
不代表你有能力逮捕我
You really want Section 31 want me- -
你真想讓31區 讓我
dogging you until the end of time?
一直追著你不放嗎
Boring.
真無聊
The past always catches up with you.
過去總會追上你
And as much as both of us
不管你我是否承認
might hate it, I'm doing you a favor.
我這是在幫你
One lqst mission.
最後一個任務
Listen.
聽著
Do you believe in fate?
你相信命運嗎
Becouse I do.
我相信
You can't hide from it.
你逃不過命運
You're nothing here, Georgiou.
你在這裡什麼都不是 喬治歐
I'm giving you a chance to get back in.
我給你機會重返戰場
In on the action on a galactic scale.
參與銀河系級別的行動
Stop running from it.
別再逃避了
Be who you are.
做回真正的自己
Or stay and tend bar for eternity.
或者繼續在這當一輩子酒保
Let's get on with it.
開始吧
Philippa Georgiou, meet my team.
菲利帕 喬治歐 來見見我的團隊
This is Melle.
這是梅勒
Zeph.
澤夫
You look like a Swiss Army knife.
你像個瑞士刀
Uh, hold on.
等等
I don't know what that means, but I'm not gonna
我不知道那是什麼 但我不會
just stand here and get insulted.
站在這被侮辱
I'm not talking about you.
我說的不是你
I'm talking about your suit.
說的是你的戰甲
Um, you're new,
你是新來的
so I'm gonna just explain this one time
我就說這一次
that when you are talking about the suit,
當你說起戰甲的時候
you're talking about Zeph.
就是在說澤夫本人
- Oh.  Zeph suffers from
-噢 -澤夫患有
what we call mecha dysmorphia.
所謂的機甲畸形症
And I may not know what that is,
雖然我不知道那是什麼
but I'm also not gonna take that
但我也不會接受
from you, Quas, and personally I'm offended.
你這麼說 夸西 我很生氣
- I think you should know...- Well, it's accurate.
-你得知道... -這是事實
It's not a diagnosis. You're not a doctor.
這不是診斷結果 你又不是醫生
Zeph. Zeph, Zeph!
澤夫 澤夫 澤夫
- He knows. He knows. He knows. - Okay, fine.
-他知道 他都知道 -好吧
He knows.
他知道
He gets it. He gets it. Yes.
-他明白 他明白 -是的
Okay, what obout that Vulcan?
那個瓦肯人呢
Nobody told her?
沒人告訴她嗎
This? The thing you're talking to?
這個 你說的這個
The Vulcan's just a machine.
瓦肯人只是台機器
I'm inside.
我在裡面
Driving.
操控著它
I control the body from a backup vehicle.
我從後備載具裡控制這具身體
Yeah, something I use to get into tight spots.
用它進入一些狹小空間
Hi there.
嗨你好
I'm Fuzz.
我是弗茲
Fuzz is a Nanokin.
弗茲是奈米族
Real fun- loving guy.
很有趣的傢伙
Hello.
你好
Except for when he's not.
除了他發起瘋來的時候
Then he's deranged with an anger management problem.
那時他就失控 有暴力傾向
Well, you could've stopped at the first thing, Quasi.
你說第一點就夠了 夸西
A bootleg Vulcan conveyance?
盜版瓦肯載具
You must see cool stuff on the black market.
黑市上一定有不少好東西
Nanokins are pretty scavengery.
奈米族都愛撿破爛
31 made first contact when
31區第一次接觸他們
we discovered an infestation on a derelict ship.
是在一艘廢棄飛船上發現了他們的寄生
Quasi. Oh, shit.
-夸西 -糟了
Say"infestation"one more time, Quasi.
再說一遍寄生 夸西
Soy"scavenger, "you sack of amorphous soot!
說啊 叫我撿破爛的 你這團黑灰
l- ls- - I heard it as soon as I said it.
我...說完我就後悔了
I will kick your ass
我要揍你
until you cannot form a solid mass of...
揍到你連個形狀都凝聚不了
Fuzz. Fuzz. Lock it down.
弗茲 弗茲 冷靜
I am locked down.
我很冷靜
I'm trapped inside a giant robot Vulcan head.
我被困在這個巨大的機器瓦肯頭裡
No one is more locked down than me right now!
還有誰比我更冷靜
Nanokins have o wonky emotional spectrum.
奈米族的情緒波動很奇怪
No, no, no, no, no, no, Iwillnot
不 不 我不會
be condescended to, Melle,
接受你的輕視 梅勒
particularly not by you, because honest.
尤其是你 說實話…
Ilove you. You are everything.
我愛你 你太完美了
Does my spectrum work for you? -  Fuzz.
-我這情緒你喜歡嗎 -弗茲
- Imean, like, like, are you into it or...- Fuzz!
-就是說 你覺得如何… -弗茲
Fuzz!
弗茲
She's insulting you, pal.
她在羞辱你 伙伴
I know Deltans are gonna do their Deltan thing,
我知道德爾塔人就這德行
but have a little self- respect, would you?
但你也該有點自尊吧
Can we continue?
我們繼續嗎
And that's Lieutenant Rachel Gorrett.
這位是瑞秋 加勒特中尉
She is detailed to Section 31 for this one mission only.
她只為這次任務臨時加入31區
Who did you piss off to get stuck in black ops, Lieutenant?
你得罪了誰才來黑ops的 中尉
Starfleet is here to make sure we color inside the lines.
星際艦隊是來確保我們守規矩的
Starfleet is here to defend the Federation,
星際艦隊是來保衛聯邦
keep the peace and make sure no one commits murder.
維護和平 防止謀殺發生的
And you? - One moment.
-那你呢 -等一下
Quasi came on my radar
夸西進入我的視野
when he proved the existence of glioclusters.
是因為他證實了神經簇的存在
Glioclusters are theoretical.
神經簇只是理論上存在
Formerly theoretical.
曾經是理論上存在
Life is just branching possibilities.
生命就是無數分支的可能性
You know, they bloom and blossom any way you can imagine.
你知道它們會以你想像不到的方式綻放
For example, I could be intimidated by you right now.
比如說 我現在可能會被你嚇到
I mean, after all, you've murdered
畢竟 你殺過
so many people.
那麼多人…
and you seem to be staring right into my soul.
而你似乎正在洞穿我的靈魂
I could respond to that
我可以對此做出回應
or I could observe my feelings right now,
或者我可以觀察當下的感受
lock it away and do what I need to do.
把它鎖起來 專注於該做的事
- Or...- Quas. Pick one. umm?
或者…夸斯 選一個吧
Yes. Sometimes Quasi sees
好的 有時夸斯會看到
so many options he gets brain- freeze. - Thank you, Melle.
太多選擇而大腦當機 謝謝你 梅勒
- Quasi, can we carryon, please?
夸斯 我們繼續好嗎 嗯
Our target's name is Dqda Noe.
我們的目標是達達 諾伊
Dubious moral compass.
道德觀念成問題
Ran a pathology lab on the Watt Colonies before he went rogue.
他曾在瓦特殖民地經營一家病理實驗室 後來叛逃了
Since then, he's been designing bioweapons on spec.
從那以後 他一直在按需設計生物武器
Noe's on his way to the Baraam to sell his latest creation
諾伊正在前往巴拉姆 準備把他最新的作品
to the Minosian High Council.
賣給米諾斯最高議會
There are no formal hostilities with the Minosian Sway,
雖然我們與米諾斯勢力沒有正式敵對
but that could change if they get their hands
但如果他們得到這種
on a superweapon.
超級武器 情況就會改變
Dowe know what this bio superweapon is?
我們知道這種生物超級武器是什麼嗎
No, but if Dada Noe is selling it, it's bad.
不知道 但既然是達達 諾伊在賣 肯定很糟
So you're here to make sure the sale never happens.
所以你們要確保這筆交易不會發生
How?
怎麼做
Things went south when you spotted us,
雖然你發現我們時計劃出了差錯
but the plan is still solid.
但計劃依然可行
First, Alok was going to...
首先 阿洛克要...
You can soy it.
你可以說出來
Connect.
搭訕
With you.
你
Welcome! Yes.
歡迎光臨 嗯
What o cute idea.
多可愛的想法
Once we had you suitably distracted,
趁你被分散注意力時
Quasi would do the other thing Quasi does.
夸斯就能做他擅長的另一件事
Okay, Quasi.
好了 夸斯
If you would do the honors. Absolutely.
請開始吧 當然
Let's get to work.
讓我們開工吧
Welcome, Dada Noe.
歡迎 達達 諾伊
This is where Fuzz comes in.
這就到了弗茲登場的時候
You wouldn't believe the tiny spots I can get into.
你不會相信我能鑽進多小的地方
For example, the inner workings of body modifications.
比如 體型改造裝置的內部結構
Oh, once I fly inside Dada's body mod,
一旦我飛進達達的體型改造裝置
well, then it's time to get to work.
就該大顯身手了
So many circuits.
那麼多電路
So many things that could go wrong.
那麼多可能出錯的地方
Competency crusader here will talk me through
這位能力至上主義者會指導我
the tech on the implant.
植入物的技術細節
And if I think we're putting Dada Noe's life in danger
如果我覺得改動那個植入物會
by tinkering with that implant,
危及達達 諾伊的生命
I will unleash the full weight of Starfleet
我就會讓星際艦隊全面介入
on this whole operotion.
這次行動
Oy, we're talking about a bloke who's selling superweapons
拜託 我們說的可是個把超級武器賣給
to any third- rate terrorist with a Lotinum card.
任何有拉錫姆卡的三流恐怖分子的傢伙
Listen carefully, Junkyard.
聽好了 廢品佬
Starfleet does not do assassinotions.
星際艦隊不做暗殺
Ay, don't get your prime directives in a bunch.
得了 別把你的主要指令搞得一團亂
You are not going to get your hands dirty
你不會弄髒自己的手
and mess up your chances of becoming captain.
破壞自己成為艦長的機會
I'm atop- tier science officer.
我可是頂尖的科學官
Butt pretzel. - : Tight- ass.
蠻橫的傢伙 死板鬼
So disrespectful.
真沒禮貌
Soon as Garrett and Fuzz sever that link.
等加勒特和弗茲切斷那個連接…
...he'll be under our control, and I'll take him down
他就會被我們控制 我會在澤夫的幫助下
with the help of Zeph.
制服他 嗯
That's what I callahit. - One.
這才叫打擊 一個
Dada Noe and his pathogen will be in custody
在買家到達巴拉姆之前
before the buyers cqn even show up to the Baraam.
達達 諾伊和他的病原體就會被捕
And we are in nd out.
我們進去又出來
Mm. Meh.
嗯 不過…
Meh?
不過
I have o simpler idea.
我有個更簡單的主意
Welcome, Monsieur Dada Noe.
歡迎 諾伊先生
We're honored to have you here at the Bqraam.
很榮幸您光臨巴拉姆
I am Veronique du Franc, the proprietor.
我是維羅妮克 杜弗朗克 這裡的主人
I told them to have my suite ready.
我說過要準備好我的套房
Mais oui, monsieur.
當然 先生
May lescort you to your quarters?
讓我帶您去房間
Come.
來吧
We have the most exquisite
我們有最精緻的…
I can't believe you're trusting this sociopath.
我不敢相信你會相信這個反社會者
Well, Lieutenant,
好吧 中尉
you got to do what you got to do,
你得做該做的事
and l'm kind of familiar with sociopaths.
而我對反社會者還挺熟悉的
I said don't bring me.
我說過不要帶我來
I trust your trip was without incident, monsieur.
希望您一路順風 先生
Well, your people made everything easy.
你們的人確實把一切都安排得很妥當
Our pleasure. Here we are.
這是我們的榮幸 到了
So tacky.
真俗氣
But I guess that's what you're known for.
不過這就是你的風格
What's this?
這是什麼
It's called a phase pod.
這叫相位艙
A client of mine gave it to me as a gift,
我的一個客戶送給我的
and I got one for myself, too.
我也給自己弄了一個
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼
Everything in the universe vibrates
宇宙中的一切都以
- on acertain wavelength. -
特定的波長振動
Damn it.
該死
Give me back my case.
把箱子還給我
No.
不
That's coming out of your security deposit.
這要從你的安全押金裡扣除
The phase pod changes the wavelength
相位艙會改變
of whatever they touch.
它們接觸物體的波長
I am out of phase with you, and you're out of phase with me.
我與你相位不同 你也與我相位不同
Iam, however, in phase with your case.
但我與你的箱子相位相同
And I will be taking it with me.
我要把它帶走
You have no idea what you've started.
你不知道你惹上了什麼麻煩
Whoops
糟糕了
lmpressive.
令人印象深刻
Are you sure you're human?
你確定你是人類嗎
Most days.
大多數時候是
Thank you.
謝謝
Give me the case.
把箱子給我
Who are you?
你是誰
He went that way. That way, that woy, that way, that way!
他往那邊跑了 那邊 那邊 那邊 那邊
Oh, aliens.
天啊 是外星人
- Naked aliens. -  Go, Zeph, go.
-赤身裸體的外星人 -快追 澤夫
He's headed to the lounge. Man, they're moving fast.
他朝休息室去了 天啊 他們跑得真快
: Melle, he's coming to you.
梅勒 他朝你那邊去了
Yikes.
天啊
No, it's okoy.
沒事
- l'm all right. - Melle, you got him?
-我沒事 -梅勒 抓到他了嗎
Got him.
抓到了
Ooh- la- la!
哇喔
Ay, amor.
天啊
That's not possible.
這不可能
I had that destroyed.
我明明銷毀了它
No. No!
不 不
lt's not possible.
這不可能
You knew that weapon.
你認識那件武器
What is it?
那是什麼
Fine. The hard way.
好吧 那就來硬的
The Eternal Supplicant begs opproach.
永恆祈求者請求覲見
You have my permission.
准予覲見
AlI hail Her Most Imperial Majesty,
至高無上的陛下
Mother of the Fatherland,
祖國之母
Overlord of Vulc- What is it?
-火山星的統治者 -什麼事
lt is finished, Your Majesty.
已經完成了 陛下
Where are my engineers?
我的工程師們呢
: They...they took their own lives upon completion.
他們…完工後就自盡了
Who is the tear for, San?
桑 你為誰而哭
Speak.
說吧
lt is for you, Majesty.
為您而哭 陛下
lt is oll
這一切都是…
for you.
為了您
I asked you a question, San.
我問你 桑
Why do you cry for me?
你為何為我哭泣
Look ot me.
看著我
Do you remember who we were?
你還記得我們是誰嗎
Before oll this.
在這一切之前
The curious boy.
那個求知若渴的男孩
The innocent girl.
那個天真無邪的女孩
I only remember my failure, Majesty.
我只記得我的失敗 陛下
Don't lie to me.
別對我撒謊
We were the only ones who could understand
只有我們能理解
the cost to stay alive.
活下去需要付出的代價
We made o team.
我們是一個團隊
We needed each other, didn't we?
我們互相需要 不是嗎
What did we say to carry each other through,
為了一起活下去
to survive together?
我們說過什麼
We are two.
我們是二…
But one.
為一體
We are two but one.
我們是二為一體
If I said then,
如果那時我說
"Let's run away,
”讓我們逃走吧
"let's flee this competition
逃離這場競爭
and everything that binds us to Terra, "
逃離一切束縛我們的地球”
what would you have said?
你會說什麼
The timing of your question is more poetic than you know.
您這個問題的時機比您想像的更富詩意
I would have said yes.
那時的我會說好
Then.
那時
But now?
但現在呢
You could have made something beautiful with your reign.
您本可以締造一個美好的統治
lnstead, you chose to build this.
但您卻選擇建造這個
That means that innocent girl I knew,
這意味著我認識的那個
she hqs been...
天真無邪的女孩
: ...murdered.
已經…死了
What is this?
這是什麼
You......
你…
You took the same poison?
你也服了同樣的毒
No! I forbid you to die!
不 我不允許你死
No one wants to live
沒有人願意活在
in your world, Emperor.
您的世界裡 皇帝陛下
You ore a monster!
您是個暴君
And what delightful place is this?
這又是什麼好地方
A safe house.
安全屋
But maybe not so safe for you.
但對你來說可能不太安全
You are Section 31.
你是31區的人
Why aren't you torturing answers out of me?
為什麼不用刑逼我說出答案
You're a tyrant.
你是個暴君
A real one.
真正的暴君
Torture wouldn't work.
刑訊對你沒用
How do you know so much about people like me?
你為什麼如此了解像我這樣的人
You learned tyranny somewhere, and you learned hard.
你也曾經歷過暴政 而且記憶深刻
If you have to hide it, that's a weakness.
如果你要隱藏這點 就是軟弱
And I can't have thot in o partner.
而我的搭檔不能軟弱
- We're not partners. - No?
-我們不是搭檔 -不是嗎
I've been very helpful.
我幫了很大忙
You had a plan that couldn't work.
你的計劃本行不通
I gave you a better one.
我給了你更好的方案
You gave me a tqste of the action,
讓你嚐到了行動的滋味
knowing I'd want more.
知道你會想要更多
You need me.
你需要我
You chose me.
你選擇了我
Why?
為什麼
Whatever you believed your mission was,
不管你以為你的任務是什麼
it's worse than you thought.
情況比你想像的更糟
Blllions of lives are at stake, and time is short.
數十億人命危在旦夕 時間緊迫
Tell me you, and I will tell you me.
你說你的故事 我就說我的
The only way this works is if I know
這件事要成功 我必須
exactly who I'm dealing with.
完全了解我在和誰打交道
I'm not from this time, either.
我也不是這個時代的人
I was born on Earth, 20th century.
我生於20世紀的地球
You are 350 years old?
你有350歲了
More or less.
差不多吧
I slept most of that time.
我沉睡了大部分時間
After my exile.
在我被流放後
The Eugenics Wars.
優生戰爭時期
Augments.
強化人…
took my planet.
奪走了我的星球
My home.
我的家園
There was maybe ten of us who fought.
當時我們只有十來個人在戰鬥
Everyone I knew either took a bullet or a blade.
我認識的人要嘛中彈要嘛被砍死
But I gave some back.
但我也殺了不少敵人
She noticed me.
她注意到了我
The Augment who slaughtered my family.
那個屠殺我家人的改造人
They called her Giri the Morked.
他們稱她為“有印記的吉裡”
She took me in.
她收留了我
Made me stronger than any human should be.
讓我變得比常人更強大
She ripped me opart
她把我撕碎
and turned me into another Augment for her army.
改造成她軍隊裡的另一個改造人
And I did terrible things.
我做了很多可怕的事
AlI for a monster like you.
都是為了像你這樣的魔頭
Because for tyrants, there is only one choice:
因為對暴君來說 只有一個選擇
murder.
殺戮
You haven't killed me.
你還沒有殺我
Yet.
暫時沒有
I recognized the weapon because I ordered it to be built.
我認出了那件武器 因為是我下令製造的
Gather your people.
召集你的人
We're gonna need every one of them.
我們需要所有人手
In my universe, there were always plotters.
在我的宇宙裡 總有人在密謀
Always a coup.
總有政變
So I built a weapon to end all threots.
所以我打造了一件武器來消滅所有威脅
I called it the Godsend.
我稱它為天賜
It triggers a chain reaction,
它會引發連鎖反應
like a virus passing between planets.
像病毒一樣在行星間傳播
Everything in its poth incinerates.
所經之處 盡成灰燼
An entire quadrant would be lost.
整個象限都會毀滅
If my enemies managed to kill me,
如果我的敵人設法殺死我
there would be nothing left to rule.
就再無統治的土地
Yeah, hi. Quick question.
呃 打擾一下 問個問題
Sorry.
抱歉
Yeah, no. Uh, justaqu it's just a quick one.
對 就是 呃 就一個小問題
Is it Godsend or God's End?
是天賜還是天譴？
Godsend or God's End?
天賜還是天譴？
I don't heara difference in what you're saying.
我聽不出你說的有什麼區別
Really? Really? Godsend. God's End.
真的嗎？真的嗎？天賜 天譴
Yeah, I'm still not getting it. - The Godsend is...
-我還是聽不出來 -天賜是…
Wait, Godsend. I hear it now.
等等 天賜 我現在聽出來了
lt's Godsend. No apostrophe. Send.
-是天賜 沒有譴字 -賜
The Godsend is here.
天賜就在這裡
How? lt's from another universe.
怎麼可能？它來自另一個宇宙
I don't know, but that man had it.
我不知道 但那個人有它
The one that you think is Dada Noe.
就是你認為是達達諾的人
The one we know is Dada Noe.
我們知道他就是達達諾
No, he's not your Dada Noe. He cqn't be.
不 他不是你們的達達諾 不可能是
He's from the Terran Empire, and he brought the Godsend here.
他來自帝聯 而且帶來了天賜
That's the only way he can know about it.
這是他知道天賜的唯一原因
And since we have him locked up tight,
既然我們已經把他關起來了
- I'II interrogate him. No, no, no.
-我來審問他 -不 不 不
We cannot trust a single word this woman says. Yeah.
-我們不能相信這個女人說的任何話 -對
She cost us Melle.
她害死了梅勒
She's the only one who knows what we're dealing with.
她是唯一知道我們在對付什麼的人
Yeah, well, so she says, little bro.
是啊 這是她說的 小弟
Little? -
小弟？
Scale- shamer!
歧視我們小個子！
Microbes outlasted dinosaurs!
微生物可比恐龍活得久！
Calm your boots. What I'm saying is...
冷靜點 我是說…
I will piss in your suit until you go all rusty like!
我要尿你一身 讓你生鏽！
...that she's the reason this is dll bollixed up.
...她才是搞砸一切的原因
She's the reason Melle's dead, and she's the reason
梅勒死是因為她 我們在銀河系屁股眼
we're in the ass end of the galaxy.
也是因為她
Listen up.
都聽著
Georgiou and I are gonna go back to the ship.
我和喬治歐要回船上去
Dada Noe is our only link to the Godsend,
達達諾是我們找到天賜的唯一線索
so we're gonna have a little chat with him.
所以我們要和他談談
What?
怎麼了？
Her name is Philippa Georgiou,
她是菲利帕 喬治歐
Her Most Imperial Majesty.
至高無上的帝國陛下
Mother of the Fatherland.
祖國之母
Overlord of Vulcan.
瓦肯的統治者
Dominus of Qo'noS, Regina Andor,
克林貢的主宰 安多星的女王
Philippa Georgiou Augustus laponius Centarius.
菲利帕 喬治歐 奧古斯都 雅波尼烏斯 森塔利烏斯
Cool.
厲害
That come with fries?
還送薯條嗎？
: That was good, right?
不錯吧？
Okay.
好吧
Every time you don't answer her questions directly,
每次你不直接回答她的問題
Her Majesty will punch you in your face.
陛下就會打你的臉
: Fine.
好吧
I'm Doda.
我是達達
Dada Noe. just Dada, then Noe.
達達諾 就是達達 然後是諾
That's it. No in- betweens.
就這樣 中間沒別的
And l, uh.
然後我...
I used to run a pathology lab in the Watt Colonies.
我以前在瓦特殖民地管理一個病理實驗室
What the shit, man? !
搞什麼鬼啊？！
You said that she was gonna be doing the face punching!
你說她會打我臉的！
So now we both have lied. You are not that Doda.
現在我們都說謊了 你不是那個達達
You're what these people call his Mirror.
你是他們所說的鏡像
You came here from the Terran Empire,
你來自帝聯
and you brought the Godsend.
帶來了天賜
What's the Godsend?
什麼是天賜？
My own war council tried to depose me.
我的戰爭委員會想要廢黜我
Do you know how I convinced the field marshal to talk?
你知道我是怎麼讓元帥開口的嗎？
I was an administrator
我是帝國武器設施
at an Imperial weapons facility on Terra.
的一名行政官員
Uh, yeah.
嗯 對
The Godsend was stored at my facility.
天賜就存放在我的設施裡
Most thought it was a legend, but I knew it was real.
大多數人以為它只是個傳說 但我知道它是真的
So you tried to sell it.
所以你想把它賣掉
Yeah, yeah.
對 對
I wanted to Iive here quietly on its proceeds.
我想靠賣它的錢在這裡安靜地生活
How did you get to our universe?
你是怎麼來到我們的宇宙的？
There was an ion storm.
有一場離子風暴
Two of them, actually.
實際上是兩場
And when they converged, which they do like clockwork,
當它們按規律匯聚時
they ripped something open on the fringes of the Empire- -
在帝國邊緣撕開了什麼東西－
an anomaly, they called it- but it was a passageway
他們稱之為異象 但其實是一條通道
to get to this place from the Terran Empire.
可以從帝聯到達這個地方
Comes out through your Crescent Nebula.
它通向你們的新月星雲
Few know obout it. For now.
知道的人很少 暫時是這樣
But it'll open again in four hours.
但它四小時後會再次打開
That's when I was supposed to be meeting my buyer.
那時我本該和買家見面
Are you aware of what that weapon does?
你知道那武器會造成什麼後果嗎？
The Terran Empire's burned through its resources.
帝聯已經耗盡了資源
There's famine.
到處都是饑荒
Entire ecologies are collapsing.
整個生態系統都在崩潰
They need to find a new territory
他們需要找到新的領地
to conquer and strip- mine.
來征服和掠奪
When they realize that their superweapon is gone,
當他們發現超級武器不見了
they're gonna find that passageway- -
他們就會找到那條通道
you know they will and they'll come
你知道他們一定會的
and they'll burn everything they touch and enslave the rest,
他們會燒毀一切 奴役倖存者
because that's what the Empire does, Majesty.
陛下 這就是帝國的作風
: They learned well from you.
他們都是跟你學的
Who else wants it?
還有誰想要它
I- I don't know, man.
我不知道 老兄
I got an offer. The money was real.
我收到了報價 錢是真的
Someone stole the Godsend from us.
有人從我們這偷走了天賜武器
- Who was he? -  No idea.
他是誰 不知道
Whoever broke into my room, whoever stole that weapon,
不管是誰闖入我的房間 偷走了武器
they know what they know because they learned it
他們之所以知道這些
from one of you.
是從你們中的某個人那學來的
Emergency transporter.
緊急傳送器
Well, this is great.
好吧 這很棒
Oh, even better.
哦 更妙了
Is that...is that the ship? Is the ship gone?
那是…那是飛船嗎 飛船不見了嗎
I liked that ship.
我喜歡那艘船
What hoppened?
發生什麼事了
Sabotage.
破壞行動
What?
什麼
Whoever stole the Godsend had a partner.
偷走天賜武器的人有個幫手
lt was someone here.
就在這裡
Which means one of us is a mole.
這意味著我們中間有個內鬼
Could be you. Could be you.
可能是你 也可能是你
If it were me,
如果是我
I would have murdered all of you already.
你們早就都死了
Look, boss, if there's a mole, you know it's not me.
老大 如果有內鬼 你知道不是我
I mean, that sounds pretty moley to me.
這話聽起來就像內鬼會說的
- I don'tknow.
我不知道
We've been on like ten ops together.
我們一起執行過十次任務了
Yeah, andI still don't even know what you look like, do I?
是啊 我連你長什麼樣都不知道
No one knows what a Chameloid looks like.
沒人知道變形者的本來面目
- You might change into anything you want. - What about Fuzz, huh?
你可以變成任何樣子 那弗茲呢
He exists on a whole other scale than anybody else. - Mm, deflecting?
他和我們完全不是一個量級的 轉移話題了
My wife is about to Iay our first litter of egg sacs.
我老婆快要產下我們的第一窩卵囊了
No, Ihave190, 000 hatchlings on the way- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
不 我即將有19萬個幼崽 等等等等
...and I want them to live. Well, look,
我希望它們能活下來 聽著
you could find a motive for any of us.
你能給我們每個人都找到動機
Or it could be a combination of any of you.
也可能是我們中任意幾個人聯手
You know, like- like Zeph and- and Fuzz or...
比如說澤夫和弗茲或者…
You are spinning out without Melle.
沒有梅勒你就亂了分寸
You cannot land on a choice.
你無法做出決定
Maybe you're putting that in my head because you're the mole.
也許你說這話是因為你就是內鬼
Huh? How obout Garrett? She's new.
嗯 加勒特怎麼樣 她是新人
She doesn't care obout us.
她根本不在意我們
I'm Starfleet.
我是星際艦隊的人
Whoa. Anyone else feel that heroic breeze right there
哇 剛才有誰感覺到英雄氣息
ruffling her cape?
吹動她的斗篷了嗎
Okay, there's an old ship out there,
好吧 那邊有艘舊船
an old garbage scow.
一艘廢棄的運輸船
Yeah, Ifound it when you were up there
是的 當你在上面
interrogating metal head.
審問鐵頭的時候我發現的
Must be years since anyone flew it,
雖然多年沒人駕駛了
but I think we can work with it
但我覺得我們可以用它
to go after whoever took the Godsend.
去追那個偷走天賜武器的人
Mm. Idislike you less.
嗯 我對你的厭惡減輕了
If I wanted someone to like me, I'd get a dog.
想讓人喜歡我 我會養條狗
I like order.
我喜歡秩序
I like prediction and conclusion.
我喜歡可預測性和結局
Then you're on the wrong team because we've got mole,
那你找錯隊伍了 因為我們這有內鬼
stranded on a dead planet,
被困在一個死寂的星球上
no communication with the outside,
無法與外界聯繫
and less than four hours before the Terrans get the Godsend
不到四小時泰倫人就能得到天賜武器
and use it anywhere in the galaxy.
他們可以在銀河系任何地方使用它
Speaking of which, Quas, what about the antenna array?
說到這個奎斯 天線陣列怎麼樣
Uh, well
呃 這個…
Well, it's a couple decades out of date.
它已經過時二十年了
We get it up and running, then we tell 31 what's coming.
我們得讓它運轉起來 然後通知31部門即將發生的事
We work together.
我們一起行動
Everyone stoys in sight. -  Yeah.
所有人都要保持在視線範圍內 好的
just.
就是…
Let's go.
我們走吧
Well, there goes that idea.
好吧 這個主意泡湯了
Our little mole has been really busy.
我們的小內鬼真是忙個不停
Ripped up all the wiring.
把所有線路都破壞了
Two teams. I'll Iead one into the woods.
分兩隊 我帶一隊進樹林
Three to see if we can salvage that scow.
三個人去看看能否修好那艘破船
You stay here with the others
你和其他人留在這
and try and fix the antenna array.
試著修復天線陣列
Why is she giving us orders now?
她憑什麼現在給我們下命令
Because I'm Ietting her
因為我允許她這麼做
and l'm pretty certain she's not the mole.
而且我很確定她不是內鬼
You wouldn't bet on a horse named Pretty Certain.
你不會押注在一匹叫“確定”的馬上
Quas, Fuzz, you get to the scow right away with Georgiou.
奎斯 弗茲 你們馬上和喬治歐去檢查那艘船
Zeph and Garrett, you stay here with me.
澤夫和加勒特留在這裡和我一起
We'll take care of the antenna array.
我們負責天線陣列
Uh, I'm sorry.
呃 抱歉
I'm supposed to go out into the woods
我要和兩個想殺我的人
with two people who want to kill me?
一起去樹林裡
Just stay in sight of each other and don't get dead.
保持在彼此視線範圍內 別死就行
Okay?
好嗎
Yep, thanks, Cap.
好的 謝謝隊長
I mean, just fifty- fifty shot one of them wants to kill me,
我是說 只有一半機率其中一個想殺我
and then 25%, just get your ass out there.
然後25%... 奎斯 趕緊滾出去
Ilove you, too, Cop.
我也愛你 隊長
AII righty.  Aye, aye.
好了 遵命
The internal circuitry on this old scow
這艘破船的內部線路
is still in decent shape.
狀況還算不錯
Everything I'm seeing should work.
我看到的部件都能用
So this thing we're chasing, the Godsend,
所以這個我們在追的東西 天賜武器
your engineers, did they install a fail- safe?
你們的工程師有沒有裝保險裝置
Can we disable it remotely?
我們能遠程禁用它嗎
There is no fail- safe. I wouldn't allow it.
沒有失控保護 我不會允許這種東西
How very on- brand for you.
這很符合你的風格
Can I ask you one more question?
我能再問一個問題嗎
I'mjust gonna ask you one more question.
我就再問最後一個
So you brought the Godsend into the world
你把神賜帶到這個世界上
to vaporize quadrillions of lives.
就為了消滅億萬生命
Never thought that was a little, you know, much?
從沒覺得這有點 你懂的 過分嗎
I ordered it destroyed.
我下令銷毀了它
And someone hid it. Your own people betrayed you.
有人藏起來了 你的人背叛了你
Well, your corporate culture was straight- up shit.
你的企業文化爛透了
And you didn't answer my question.
而且你還沒回答我的問題
The asymptote coil is gone.
漸近線線圈不見了
Someone must have scavenged it for the terbium.
有人一定是為了鋱把它拆走了
Well, find another one, this thing should fly.
找另一個這東西應該能飛
Maybe the cargo hull. Huh. Oh, no, no.
-貨艙裡可能有 -不行
Everyone stays together, all right?
所有人要在一起 明白嗎
Limits the possibilities of you killing us.
這樣你就沒機會殺我們了
Let's go to the cargo hold, please.
我們去貨艙看看
Aren't you coming?
你不來嗎
Yes. Icouldn't be more excited.
來 我可太期待了
Yeah, Icould help you down there, of course,
我當然可以幫你
but considering how, you know, control
但是考慮到你知道 控制欲
is central to your entire identity
是你性格的核心
and the fact that I'm just not good atit,
而我又不擅長這個
I'mjust gonna stand here and honor our relationship
我就站在這裡 尊重我們的關係
by doing absolutely nothing.  Helpful.
-什麼都不做 -很有幫助
It's called radical self- acceptance.
這叫徹底的自我接納
Evolved of you. Well, thank you.
-你很開明嘛 -謝謝
So, can you fix it?
你能修好嗎
I'm not even sure it's broken. lt's just missing a part.
我都不確定它是不是壞了 只是缺了個零件
Look, this- this torn wiring Iooks dramatic,
你看 這些斷裂的線路看著嚇人
but this equipment has redundancy built in.
但這設備有備用系統
There's an easy work- around.
有簡單的替代方案
Except somebody ripped out the the tq junction.
但TQ介面被人扯掉了
Other than that, this thing should work.
除此之外 這東西應該能用
Okay, well, maybe our mole has it.
那也許內鬼拿著它
Garrett? - Yeah.
-加勒特？ -嗯
Zeph.
澤夫
Where is Zeph?
澤夫在哪
Zeph, come in.
澤夫 收到請回復
Zeph, do you copy?
澤夫 聽到請回話
Zeph.
澤夫
Garrett, was that you?
加勒特 是你弄的嗎
Garrett, what the hell was that?
加勒特 那是什麼聲音
Someone just activated the antenno array.
有人啟動了天線陣列
Damn it.
該死
What's happening?
發生什麼事了
Garrett, sitrep.
加勒特 匯報情況
This is going to be good.
這下有好戲看了
Lieutenant, do you copy? Over.
中尉 收到請回復 完畢
Clear.
安全
Nothing here.
這裡沒有
How could someone have used this to send out a signal?
怎麼可能有人用這個發送信號
lmpossible. lt's missing a part.
不可能 它缺了個零件
And someone shot it to hell.
而且被人打壞了
I heard someone running.
我聽到有人在跑
Zeph must have put the thetq junction back in.
澤夫一定是把theta介面裝回去了
Then shot it after he used the array.
用完天線陣列後又打壞了它
So he must hove circled back after he went AWOL.
他失蹤後一定是繞回來了
Zeph came down to this planet to sabotage us.
澤夫來這個星球就是為了破壞我們的行動
And now that we're stranded,
現在我們被困在這裡
he sent a message to whoever he's working with.
他給他的同夥發了訊息
And he'll lay low until his ride gets here,
他會躲起來等援軍到了
and then he's long gone.
然後就跑得無影無蹤
Then we need to find him first.
那我們得先找到他
Observer, do you copy?
觀察手 收到請回復
Please, Raider One, when do I not copy?
突擊一號 我什麼時候沒收到過
That's funny. Status?
有意思 情況如何
I'm picking up a lot of interference,
這裡干擾很大
but the tricorder shows Zeph's biosignature
但三錄儀顯示澤夫的生命特徵
was just in this sector. Over.
剛剛出現在這個區域 完畢
Copy. Stay low and tight, people.
收到 保持隱蔽 跟緊點
The warlord you served, Giri, what happened to her?
你效忠的軍閥吉裡 她怎麼了
She died like she lived.
她死得跟活著一樣
By that, you know what I mean.
你知道我什麼意思
She was lucky.
她很幸運
She wasn't infected with a conscience.
沒被良心感染
lnfected? - Yeah.
-感染？-對
A monster can only be a monster.
怪物就該是怪物
A monster with regrets is useless.
有悔意的怪物毫無用處
Mm. So that's why you were hiding
所以你才躲在
in a bar ot the ass end of nowhere.
那個鳥不生蛋的酒吧裡
Maybe it's why you're working with 31.
也許這就是你為什麼要跟31部門合作
To wipe your slate clean.
為了洗清自己
There's always a price to pay for people like us.
像我們這樣的人總要付出代價
You wouldn't be here if you didn't agree.
你在這裡就說明你也同意
Oh, so that's why you chose me.
原來你是這麼看我的
You think I'm a monster who feels enough to be controlled
你覺得我是個有感情能被控制的怪物
but still do the real dirty work.
但還能幹骯髒事
No, I think you want the Godsend back because you know
不我覺得你想要回神賜是因為你知道
it's your one chance to redeem yourself
這是你唯一的機會
for all the shit you've done.
彌補你的罪過
I want the Godsend bock because it's mine.
我要回神賜是因為它是我的
Ah. Zeph's exoskeleton is Ieaking.
啊 澤夫的外骨骼在漏水
Yep, more.
對越來越多了
This way.
這邊
Blip, Clip,
布利普 克利普
Grip,
格利普
Polio, lnfluensina,
小兒麻痺 流行感冒
- Cowpox...- What are you saying?
-牛痘… -你在說什麼
I'm reciting the names of me hatchlings.
我在給我的孩子們取名字
Since one of you is going to murder me,
既然你們中有人要殺我
I'm never gonna meet them, but at Ieast I can honor them
我永遠見不到他們了 但至少我可以一一紀念他們
one by one.
每一個
Trip,
崔普
Trip 2,
崔普2號
Tonsilyitis, Crimean Congo Hemorrhagic Fever...
扁桃體炎 克里米亞－剛果出血熱…
Are you gonna sob out 190, 000 names?
你要把19萬個名字都哭訴出來嗎
How can you be so cold and insensitive?
你怎麼能這麼冷血無情
Might he have recorded what happened?
他可能記錄下發生的事了嗎
Sure.
當然有
Except the footage was probably murdered along with him.
但影像可能和他一起消失了
We could connect one of the tricorders to his suit.
我們可以把三錄儀連接到他的外骨骼上
Whatever data is left, we'll know who did this.
只要還有數據 就能知道兇手是誰
You say that like we're all suspects.
你這是在懷疑我們所有人
We're not. All right?
我們不是 好嗎
Fuzz, me and her were in the scow when all this happened-
福茲、我和她當時都在駁船上
everyone in sight of everyone else.
大家都在彼此的視線範圍內
And nobody went anywhere, right?
而且沒人離開過對吧
Right. -  umm.
-對 -嗯
Oh, this is not Zeph's.
這不是澤夫的
Brunette. 25 centimeters.
黑髮25公分
This is insane.
這太瘋狂了
Stop fidgeting.
別亂動
I've been in close quarters with Zeph for a week.
我和澤夫一起待了一週
Okay, so you're into mecha boom- boom.
好吧 你喜歡機械性愛
Lots of humans are. No shame.
很多人類都這樣 沒什麼好羞恥的
Well, that's impossible.
這不可能
Lieutenant Garrett,
加勒特中尉
why is Zeph's blood underneath your fingernails?
為什麼你的指甲下有澤夫的血
evidence from you was found on Zeph's body,
在澤夫身上發現了你的痕跡
and evidence from Zeph's body was found on you.
在你身上也發現了澤夫的痕跡
Not very Starfleet.
一點都不星際艦隊
Oh, Iam very Starfleet.
我非常星際艦隊
And you know I didn't do this.
你知道我沒做這事
You are just terrified of anyone with a moral compass.
你只是害怕任何有道德準則的人
And deep down in that pure little heart,
在那顆純潔的心底
you're actuallya chaos goblin, aren't you?
你其實是個混亂小妖精 對吧
- I know you have itin you, angel. - Don't call me that.
-我知道你有這潛力 天使 -別這麼叫我
Starfleet sniffed you out
星際艦隊看出了你的本質
and put you in a place where you'd be most useful.
把你安排在最有用的位置
Section 31 is just the place for officers who bend the rules,
31區正是那些懂得變通規則的軍官該去的地方
never quite break them until they do.
從不違規 直到他們違規的那一刻
And you fit right in here.
你在這裡很合適
You can torture me all you want.
你隨便折磨我
You will never make me o murderer.
你永遠不能把我變成殺人兇手
No.
不
We've got footage!
找到錄影了！
Stop!
住手！
This is my suit.
這是我的外骨骼
I am the suit!
我就是外骨骼！
The suit is me!
外骨骼就是我！
One second.
等一下
We were your friends. We were your friends.
我們是朋友啊 我們是朋友
You can't kill me. -
你不能殺我
Zeph, no. You can't kill...
-澤夫 不要 -你不能殺…
Zeph killed himself?
澤夫是自殺的？
Why would he do that?
他為什麼要這麼做
Sorry to disappoint you, Your Majesty.
抱歉讓你失望了 陛下
Look, none of this is making any sense.
這一切都說不通
No, none of it makes a lick of sense.
對 一點都說不通
Why would he do this? Uh.
他為什麼要這麼做 呃...
Give me a couple minutes to......- We don't have minutes.
-給我幾分鐘... -我們沒時間了
Well, then give me a couple seconds, then.
那給我幾秒鐘
Could be you.  Could be you.
-可能是你 -可能是你
And I still don't even know what you look like.
我甚至還不知道你長什麼樣
You could change into anything you want.
你可以變成任何樣子
She's new. She doesn't care about us.
她是新來的她不在乎我們
I'm Starfleet. - Whoa.
-我是星際艦隊的 -哇
When you are talking about the suit,
說到外骨骼
you're talking about Zeph.
就是在說澤夫
This isn't Fuzz.
這不是福茲
The Vulcan's just a machine, you know.
瓦肯人只是個機器 你知道的
I'm inside.
我在裡面
Scale- shamer!
歧視鱗片的人！
You wouldn't believe the tiny spots I can get into.
你想不到我能鑽進多小的地方
For example, the inner workings of body modifications.
比如 身體改造的內部構造
There's an autopilot.
有個自動駕駛
That's the only thing that makes sense.
這是唯一合理的解釋
You set the Vulcan machine on autopilot.
你把瓦肯機器設成了自動駕駛
That's why its responses were so strange.
難怪它的反應那麼奇怪
Aren't you coming? - Yes.
-你不來嗎 -來了
You flew into Zeph's exoskeleton.
你鑽進了澤夫的外骨骼
And once you were inside...
一旦進去之後…
Somebody ripped out the theta junction.
有人拆掉了西塔接頭
Garrett, where's Zeph?
加勒特 澤夫在哪
Then you took control of Zeph's suit.
然後你控制了澤夫的外骨骼
While the others were out Iooking for him,
當其他人出去找他的時候
you made him sneak back into the antenna array
你讓他偷偷回到天線陣列
and send those messages.
發送了那些資訊
Don't do this to them!
別對他們下手！
We were your friends.
我們曾是朋友啊
Then you destroyed the evidence.
然後你就毀掉了證據
And you killed Zeph.
還殺了澤夫
And then you planted the evidence on Garrett here.
然後把證據栽贓給了加勒特
Hands up, Fuzz.
舉起手來 費茲
Oh, shite and ever shite.
真是見了鬼了
Whoa. You're honestly gonna believe what she says, Alok?
你真要相信她說的話嗎 阿洛克？
Quasi, after everything we've been through?
奎斯 想想我們共同經歷的一切
C- Can Ijust say one thing first?
我…我能先說一句話嗎？
I'm still hacked into Zeph's exoskeleton.
我還能控制澤夫的機甲
Come on!
快點！
What happened to"no crew member Ieft behind"?
“絕不拋棄任何船員”呢？
Come on, come on!
快點 快點！
Get us closer.
靠近點
Igot you. Igot you.
我接住你了 我接住你了
Nice and easy.  Damn.
該死
You keep tabs on the black market, umm?
你一直在關注黑市對吧？
And that's where you heard about the Godsend.
在那裡聽說了上天之眼
Why do you care?
你在意這個幹什麼？
You killed your family.
你殺了自己的家人
What's a few billion more people, huh?
再多幾十億人又算什麼？
Where is it? And who are you working with?
它在哪裡？你在和誰合作？
You took your crown while they died in agony
你就在他們身邊十步之遙
not ten feet away.
看著他們痛苦死去時奪取了王冠
You condemned your only friend to slavery,
你把唯一的朋友變成了奴隸
and then you had the balls to offer him kindness at the end?
最後還厚顏無恥地對他施以仁慈？
How could you know that?
你怎麼會知道這些？
Glad you're catching on.
終於明白了吧
He played you, Emperor.
他騙了你 陛下
San's alive.
桑還活著
lt's not possible.
這不可能
That's not possible. How?
這怎麼可能？
He built up an immunity from that poison, you know.
他一點點服用那種毒藥
Teeny tiny doses over time.
慢慢建立起了抗體
Once again, small shite for the win, mama.
小人物又贏了一局 陛下
Where is he? !
他在哪裡？！
He's gonna put on quite the show.
他會給你上一場好戲
You built the Godsend.
你製造了上天之眼
You made this monster.
這個怪物是你一手造就
This is all you.
這都是你的錯
Be careful, all right?
小心點 知道嗎？
I said be careful.
我說了小心點
I have to get around in that.
我還要靠這個活動呢
You can afford a hundred of them now.
你現在能買上百個這樣的了
Oh, great.
哦 太好了
I'd settle for one that works.
我只要一個能用的就行
So that's it?
所以就是這個？
The almighty Godsend.
至高無上的上天之眼
When you're emperor,
等你當上皇帝後
maybe start by naming it something less confusing.
最好給它換個不那麼讓人困惑的名字
Once that passageway opens up,
一旦通道打開
he contacts the Terrans, they come through.
他就聯繫地球人 他們就會過來
They're detonating it here.
他們會在這裡引爆它
And he'd be the darling of the Empire.
他就成了帝國的寵兒
So he throws the Federotion into chaos.
他會把聯邦搞得一團混亂…
Starfleet will start scrambling.
星際艦隊會手忙腳亂
Perfect time to invode.
正是入侵的好時機
You gave birth to this thing.
你創造了這個東西
- How do we stop it? -  We don't.
我們做不到
We're trapped here, so we can't follow him.
我們被困在這裡 追不上他
The antenna's destroyed, so we can't warn anybody.
天線被毀了 警告不了任何人
That is bullshit.
這都是借囗
You can do better than that. - l can't.
我做不到
The Godsend is me.
上天之眼就是我
I'm the only one I could never defeat.
我永遠都戰勝不了自己
The past always catches up with you.
過去總會追上你
Right?
對吧？
Doesn't mean it always wins.
但不代表它總能贏
Every safe house, I have a backup plan.
每個安全屋我都有後備計劃
We'll get that scow running.
我們能讓那艘垃圾船啟動
Boss, the scow won't fly.
老大 那垃圾船飛不起來
Not without an asymptote coil.
沒有漸近線線圈不行
We have one.
我們有一個
We'll catch up with San.
我們能追上桑
We'll make sure he can't contact the Terrans.
確保他聯繫不上地球人
You ripped out the coil.
你拆了線圈
Couldn't tell you while a mole was still running around.
有內鬼在時不能告訴你們
Asshole.
混蛋
Okay, Quas, give her a rip.
好了 奎斯 啟動它
Stil just one pulse.
還是只有一個脈衝
And we're in business.
搞定了
Okay, team, we have less than 30 minutes.
好了團隊 我們只剩不到30分鐘了
Quas, set a course for the Crescent Nebula.
奎斯 設定航向新月星雲
AII right, this is gonna be bumpy and bad.
這會很顛簸 很危險
I'm assuming San's ship will be armed.
我猜桑的船上有武器吧
Yeah, every Terran ship's armed.
是啊 地球人的船都有武器
He'll have proton cannons, torpedoes,
他有質子炮 魚雷
and we are a garbage barge.
而我們只是艘垃圾船
Why are you laughing?
你笑什麼？
Because I can't imagine things getting much worse.
因為情況不會更糟了
Let's go.
我們走
So, this thing flies around in the middle of a tractor field.
這東西在牽引光束中間飛行
People jettison their garbage into space,
人們把垃圾丟進太空
and the scow flies around and drags the trash
垃圾船就在牽引光束裡飛行
along with the field.
收集這些垃圾
Once the tractor field is full,
一旦牽引光束裝滿了
it dumps the trash in the Nebula
就把垃圾倒進星雲
where it disintegrates in the rodiation.
讓輻射把它們分解掉
I just want to be clear.
我就說明這麼多
You're saying that our best potential weapon is
你是說我們最好的武器就是
a beam for collecting garbage?
一個收集垃圾的光束？
Yes. Great.
-對 -太好了
Hey, being judgy never helped anything.
嘿抱怨可解決不了問題
Where are you going? - Engineering.
-你去哪？-工程部
If that's our only weapon,
既然這是我們唯一的武器
I'II redirect all power to the tractor beams.
我要把所有能量都轉到牽引光束上
That's actually a good plan.
這主意還不錯
We're in position.
我們就位了
The passagewoy will open soon.
通道馬上就會打開
Do you know what I want when this is all over?
你知道這一切結束後我想要什麼嗎？
Just a big space, you know,
就是一個大空間
for me hatchlings to tunnel and fly around and.
讓我的幼蟲能隨意打洞和飛翔
What do you want?
你想要什麼？
I want Philippa Georgiou to marinate in her own defeat.
我要喬治歐在失敗中煎熬
I get you guys are all"eternal nemesis,
我知道你們是”永世宿敵
sexy evil tension"and stuff, but...
性感又邪惡的糾葛”之類的 但是…
Alert.
警報
lncoming vessel.
發現來襲艦船
Collision trajectory detected.
檢測到碰撞軌道
Of course she got it off the ground.
果然她把船弄起來了
I say we should use the torpedoes.
我說我們該用魚雷
They've picked us up.
他們發現我們了
Photon torpedo incoming.
光子魚雷來襲
Impact in five, fourReally want to take evqsive action right now!
-還有五秒四… -現在真該躲開！
...three, two, one. Quas, hold the course. Put everything in our shields.
-三 二 一 -夸西保持航向 全力防護罩
Why isn't she changing course?
她為什麼不改變航向？
Do I look like a fortune teller?
我又不是算命的
Do we have enough juice to drag them with the tractor beam yet?
牽引光束的能量夠用了嗎？
Yeah, but we can't take another direct hit.
夠了 但我們承受不住再一次直接命中
Incoming torpedo in five, four...
魚雷來襲 五 四…
Keep it steady. We're almost there...three, two, one.
-穩住 馬上就到了…… -三 二 一
Now.
就是現在
Alert. Navigation control suspended.
警報 導航控制暫停
What are they gonna do, drag us to death?
他們想幹嘛 把我們拖垮？
She's trying to stop me from reaching the Empire.
她想阻止我回到帝國
How's everybody feeling about this?
大家覺得這情況如何？
It's the only way.
這是唯一的辦法
This can work.
這能成功
The radiation will wear down their shields.
輻射會削弱他們的防護罩
Yeah, the thing is, the radiation hits us, too.
是啊 問題是輻射也會影響到我們
Target lock malfunction.
目標鎖定故障
Ican't get torpedo lock. Cannons offline.
無法鎖定魚雷 炮塔離線
San?
桑？
San.
桑
San!
桑！
Radiation levels critical.
輻射水平已達臨界值
Shields are down. I repeat, shields are down!
防護罩已失效 重複 防護罩已失效！
And San's?
桑的呢？
His are at 12% and falling fast.
他的只剩12% 而且還在快速下降
Plasma incoming!
電漿體來襲！
We get caught with a burst like that,
要是挨上這樣一下
and we're done.
我們就完了
This is chaos, Garrett.
這太混亂了 加勒特
You know you love it, umm?
你知道你喜歡這樣 嗯？
Mqybe let it in, make out with it a little.
也許該接受它 跟它親熱一下
lt's why Starfleet put you here.
這就是星際艦隊派你來這的原因
Chaos is my friend with benefits.
混亂就是我的炮友
Yeah, Garrett, let's get messy.
對 加勒特 讓我們玩個痛快
umm? - Okay.
-嗯？ -好啊
You got this, Quas. Uh- huh.
-交給你了 夸西 -嗯
You ready?
準備好了嗎？
San's shields are at four percent.
桑的防護罩只剩4%了
Two now.
現在是2%
His shields are down.
他的防護罩失效了
Good to go.
可以行動了
Philippa!
菲利帕！
This contest only ends
這場較量只有
when one of us is dead!
一方死去才會結束！
Detonation sequence activating.
開始引爆程序
See, the Nanokins, we don't need the Federation.
你看 我們奈米人不需要聯邦
We never have.
從來都不需要
We ruled before you behemoths found us,
在你們這些巨獸發現我們之前 我們就是統治者
and we will rule again after you're gone.
等你們消失後 我們還會繼續統治
Guess who survives very Iarge explosions.
猜猜誰能在大爆炸中存活？
Very small things.
非常小的生物
Now, if you'll excuse me, I need to cut our ship loose.
現在失陪了 我要去切斷我們的船
Sorry if your friends die in the process.
抱歉如果你的朋友因此喪命
No, I'm joking.
不 我開玩笑的
I can't wait to kill them.
我等不及要殺了他們
So long, you big lumps of shite!
再見了 你們這些大塊頭的廢物！
Who's flying that?
誰在駕駛那艘船？
Uh, according to the sensors, one tiny life- form on board,
呃 根據感測器顯示 只有一個微小的生命體
and it's heading right for us.
而且正朝我們飛來
Plot missile lock.
鎖定導彈
We have trash, all right? Just trash.
我們只有垃圾 對 就只有垃圾
But one.
只剩一個
San.
桑
Awaiting biosignature confirmation.
等待生物特徵信號確認
I've got Fuzz's shuttle.
我鎖定了法茲的太空梭
He's heading back to San's ship.
他正返回桑的船上
We're barely keeping up. - Stay on him.
-我們勉強跟上了 -別跟丟他
Uh, we don't have any weapons.
呃 我們沒有任何武器
We have a payload bay full of trash.
我們有一船艙的垃圾
Do not lose that shuttle.
別讓那艘太空梭跑了
Okay.
好的
I was nothing!
我什麼都不是
That boy was soft, weak.
那個男孩軟弱無能
But all those years under your heel taught me who I am now.
但在你的壓迫下 這些年讓我成長到今天
The Empire's coming through that portal.
帝國軍即將通過傳送門
My Empire!
我的帝國
And we will reign over this universe
我們將以仁慈統治這個宇宙
with righteous mercy, not like you!
不像你那樣殘暴
There are no benevolent dictators, San.
沒有仁慈的獨裁者 聖
You taught me that.
這是你教會我的
We can come back from this.
我們還能挽回
We can start over.
重新開始
Oh, I love chaos.
我愛混亂
Chaos is my jam.
混亂才是我的菜
I love chaos. I love chaos.
我愛混亂 我愛混亂
Garrett, what the hell are you doing down there?
加勒特 你在下面幹什麼
Quasi, I am a trained Starfleet officer
夸西 我可是受過訓練的星際艦隊軍官
who fully intends on living long enough to be captain one day.
我要活到當上艦長的那天
You got to trust me, okay?
你得相信我 好嗎
Hi there.
你好啊
I'm so glad you found me.
真高興你找到我
What'd you just say?
你剛說什麼
lt's atoy.
這是個玩具
Looks like it came from a Droom planet.
看起來像是來自德羅姆星球的
Shall we do something fun together?
我們一起玩點有趣的吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇 哇 哇 哇
You okay down there, Starfleet?
你還好吧 星際艦隊
Oh, come on, come on, come on, come on. Yes.
來吧 來吧 好
Oh, we do not let Droom tech into the Federation
我們不讓德羅姆科技進入聯邦
because they use Terrenium as a power source.
因為他們用特倫礦作為能源
Oh, you're gonna blow us up, aren't you?
你是要炸死我們對吧
You better hope that this ship's hull
最好祈禱這艘船的船體
is reinforced with Tomohite.
是用托莫海特強化的
I am a science officer.
我是個科學官
And science is just controlled chaos.
科學就是可控的混亂
Whoa, chaos, chaos, chaos, chaos, chaos!
混亂 混亂
Ah, come on.
啊 快點
Get up, you stupid robot.
起來 你這笨機器人
No. No.
不 不
No!
不
Stay in front of Fuzz's ship so we can open the payload bay.
待在費茲的船前面 這樣我們就能打開貨艙
Uh, yeah.
呃 對
About that.
關於這個
Uh, thing is...Quasi, there's about to be a very large explosion.
夸西 馬上就要發生巨大爆炸了
This console's in a language I don't know.
這控制台用的是我不認識的語言
I can decipher some of it.
我能破譯一些
I just have to break it down to morphemes
我只需要把它分解成詞素
and, you know...Large explosion impending.
然後你知道的…巨大爆炸即將發生
Either of these two buttons could open the cargo bay.
這兩個按鈕任一個都可能打開貨艙
Okay, so push them both.
那就兩個都按
Either of these two buttons could also
這兩個按鈕任一個也可能
initiate a self- destruct protocol.
啟動自毀程序
- We're gonna blow up anyway. - Uh- huh.
反正我們都要爆炸了
- Um, uh. Huh? - Quasi. Quasi, look at me.
夸西 夸西 看著我
You just need to make o call.
你只需要做個決定
You know what to do.
你知道該怎麼做
Okoy. Okay.
好吧 好
We can be friends forever...
我們可以永遠做朋友
Do you want to hear something funny?
想聽個有趣的事嗎
I'm on autopilot.
我在自動駕駛
What the hell?
見鬼了
We're all gonna die.
我們都要死了
No!
不
lt's wonderful just to be with you.
和你在一起真是太美好了
Whoo! - Whoa!
好耶
Yes!
成功
Die now.
現在就死吧
Go tell your family how much you've changed.
去告訴你的家人你變了多少
San.
聖
No. No.
不 不
No.
不
San.
聖
This is not what I want.
這不是我想要的
Please.
求你
: llove you. : llove you.
我深愛著你
San.
聖
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm so sorry.
真的很抱歉
You- you- you were right.
你...你...你說得對
I still needed you.
我仍然需要你
I alwoys needed.
我一直需要…
To show me who I am, even now.
讓你告訴我自己是誰即使到現在
Now.
現在
M- M...My emperor.
我的…我的皇帝
My love.
我的愛
No.
不
We are one.
我們合而為一
Forever.
永遠
Ion storm convergence imminent.
離子風暴即將匯聚
Passageway is opening.
通道正在開啟
Biosignature confirmed.
生物特徵信號確認
Detonation in 60 seconds.
60秒後引爆
Computer, target lock on the passogeway.
電腦 鎖定通道
Target lock confirmed.
目標鎖定確認
If you could go back,
如果能回到過去
and you were kneeling in front of Giri,
當你跪在吉裡面前時
would you kill her?
你會殺了她嗎
Would you put a stop to all the suffering and smoke forever,
你願意終結所有的痛苦和煙霧
even if it meant that you had to die?
即使這意味著你必須死去
Yes.
會
Then I'm glad I knew you, Alok Sahar.
很高興認識你 阿洛克 薩哈爾
Detonation in 30 seconds.
30秒後引爆
Passageway is open.
通道已開啟
Sensors show they've activated impulse engines.
感測器顯示他們啟動了脈衝引擎
What?
什麼
Yeah. You need to transport them back.
-快把他們傳送回來 -好
Yeah. Okay. Now.
-快 -馬上
Okay, okay, okoy, okay.
好的好的好的好的
The storm's interfering. I can't lock on to them.
風暴干擾太強 我無法鎖定他們
Detonation in ten seconds.
10秒後引爆
Come on. Come on!
來啊 快啊
They're running out of time.
他們快沒時間了
I'm trying.
我在努力
Detonation in five,
5秒後引爆
Lieutenant Gorrett?
加勒特中尉
Rachel?
瑞秋
You all right?
你沒事吧
- l'mokay. umm? You here?
-我沒事 -嗯 你在這裡
Yeah. You're alive. All right.
-是的 你還活著 -好的
Yeah, Quasi got us out.
對 奎西救了我們
There we go. There we are. -  Thank you.
-太好了 -謝謝
Oh, you did it.
你做到了
Oh, we won.
我們贏了
Oh. Grow up.
噢 成熟點
Perkiness is disgusting.
過度興奮真讓人噁心
Yeah.
是啊
I hear you.
我懂你
lt's happening.
開始了
The passageway's collapsing.
通道正在崩塌
There she is.
她來了
How was your debrief?
匯報情況如何
Oh, could've been worse.
還行 不算太糟
They made me an offer.
他們給了我一個提議
And?
然後呢
l'm sitting on it. -
我還在考慮
You?
你呢
And how long did you think
你以為這樣能瞞我
you could fool me with this, umm?
多久呢 嗯
- What gave it away?
-什麼露餡了 -嗯
You still get nervous when I look at you.
你看著我時還是會緊張
Oh. Hey, C- Cap.
呵 你好 船長
Leave that poor man alone.
別難為那個可憐人了
Virgil.
維吉爾
A round of elixirs for my friends.
給我的朋友們來一輪仙釀
Pleasure, Madame du Franc. Mm- umm.
-榮幸之至 杜弗朗克夫人 -嗯
Lieutenant Gorrett.
加勒特中尉
They let you off the ship.
他們讓你離船了
lt's actually Lieutenant Commander Garrett now.
現在是加勒特中校了
Oh. - Thank you very much.
-噢 -非常感謝
And if this unit is gonna be a permanent detail,
如果這個小隊要成為常駐編制
then you all definitely need oversight.
那你們肯定需要監管
I may slaughter you all at any moment.
我隨時可能把你們都殺了
Is that adeal- breaker?
這算個問題嗎
Nah. Whatevs.
-不算 -無所謂
It's not like you need a reason anyway.
反正你也不需要理由
- lt's true. You'reabad bitch. -
說得對 你就是個狠人
With the stare of death.  Oh, we get it.
-眼神都能殺人 -噢 我們懂
You're a terrifying, soulless murderer
你就是個可怕的無情殺手
who we can never truly trust.
我們永遠無法信任你
I love that for us.
我愛死這樣了
Somebody's got to keep things lively.
總要有人讓生活有點樂子
Touche. -  Yes, touche. You make a point.
-說得好 -對 說得好 -有道理
To us.
為我們乾杯
This isn't poison, is it?
這不會是毒藥吧
And now that you have us all here,
既然我們都在這裡了
what next?
接下來呢
Well, not quite all.
還不是全部
Ladies and gent, stage left.
女士們先生們 看左邊
You got to be kidding me.
你在開玩笑吧
Oh, I'm not Fuzz.
我不是福茲
Section 31 bought
31區在黑市上買了
two of these conveyances on the black market.
兩個這樣的運輸器
Name's Wisp. I'm his wife.
我叫薇思 是他的妻子
And I'm here for when we catch up with
等我們追上那個
that lying, double- dealing son of a bitch.
背信棄義的混蛋時就知道了
Uh, well, we blew up his ship, ma'am.
呃 我們炸了他的船 女士
- Uh, Mrs. Fuzz. Oh, honey.
-呃 福茲夫人 -噢 親愛的
Little things sometimes survive big explosions.
大爆炸中有時也會有小東西存活
And when we find him, I have questions.
等找到他 我有話要問他
- Now, what are we talking about? -  I'm glad you asked.
-說起這個 -正等你問呢
I was just letting the team know.
我正要告訴團隊
Control has a job for us.
指揮部給我們安排了任務
My better judgment has been
我的理智這兩天
screaming at me for two days now.
一直在對我大喊
It keeps saying that you lot are gonna cost me my job.
說你們這些人會害我丟掉工作
- We might. - She might.
-有可能 -她說不定會
I told my judgment to shut up
我讓理智閉嘴
and tqke a nap.
去睡覺
Cause we have work to do.
因為我們有事要做
Hqs anybody been to Turkana IV?
有人去過圖爾卡納四號嗎
- Whew.  Wait.
-呼 -等等
Did you say Turkana or say jur- jurnana?
你說圖爾卡納還是朱爾納納
He thought"Your Mama IV. "
他以為是“你媽媽四號”
Oh, Your Mama IV.
噢 你媽媽四號
No.
不是